In certain circumstances, you may find
在某些特定情况下你可能会发现
that your scatter plots are difficult to interpret.
绘制出来的散点图很难解读
You might have an extremely large number of data points such that a standard scatter plot
有时可能因为数据量太庞大 在标准散点图中绘制出来
is an undetailed blob or your numeric data might be discrete in nature,
就成了细节不明的大斑点 有时可能因为数值数据是离散型的
making it difficult to see the distribution of data.
很难观察数据分布
Can you tell what's going on in either of these plots? Me either.
你能从这两个图中看出什么信息吗？我是不行的
Conditions like this where you have too many points in
像这种小范围内挤着太多数据点的情况
a small area are called over plotting.
叫做数据点重叠
In these cases, techniques like sampling, transparency,
这种情况下 抽样、透明度调整和抖动等技术
and jitter can allow you to build scatter plots
可以帮助你处理散点图
where you can better detect patterns and relationships.
以更好地检测数据模式和相关性
Take for example, this plot of 10,000 data points
以此图为例 图中的 1 万个数据点
generated from a couple of bivariate normal distributions.
是由两个二元正态分布生成的
It's hard to tell where the drop off in density is from
我们很难根据分布峰值来确定密度下降的位置
the distribution's peaks and how fast it occurs.
和下降幅度
One way of solving this is to use random sampling to plot a smaller number of points.
一种解决方案是随机抽样 减少绘制的数据点
Let's say 800.
比如抽样 800 个数据点
We can clearly see the gap in peaks where fewer points are plotted.
数据点少了 就可以清楚地看到峰值之间的间隙了
The random selection of points still gives us
对数据点进行随机抽样
a good intuition for the general distribution of data.
并没有影响我们观察数据的总体分布
As an alternative strategy,
另外一种解决方案
we can still plot our original 10,000
我们可以仍然保留原来的一万个数据点
points but plot each point with some transparency instead.
只是修改各数据点的透明度
Each individual point will be lighter in color but when points overlap,
这样每个点的颜色都会变浅 数据点重叠的区域
the overlapped region becomes darker.
颜色则会较深
The two darkest regions are those with the highest number of
这两个颜色最深的区域数据点最多
points indicating the peaks of the distributions.
意味着这是分布的峰值
Since a higher density results in a darker color,
因为密度高会导致颜色变深
we have in an implied way,
所以我们可以间接地
used color to augment what would have been obscured from using position alone.
借助颜色来增强只用位置无法突出的重点
But what if one or both of our variables are discrete?
但如果其中一个变量 甚至两个变量都是离散型的呢？
Sampling doesn't help at all because any number of overlapping points all look the same.
此时抽样方法不再适用 因为无论有多少数据点重叠 看起来都一样
Transparency allows us to make density judgments based on
虽然我们可以调整透明度 根据颜色研究密度
color but this loses some of the power available in positional encodings.
但这样会损失一些位置信息
This is one case where we will want to add some jitter.
此时就是应用抖动技术的时机
Jittering adds a small amount of random noise to the position of each point
抖动会给各点的位置增加一点随机噪声
so that multiple data points that have the same values are now spread over a small area.
在小范围内将值相同的多个数据点抖散
As long as the jitter keeps each of the discrete values in distinct bands,
只要各离散值的抖动范围不重合
this can be a big help in the identification and interpretation of trends.
我们就能借助抖动方便地找出并解读数据趋势